ANDREW INNOCENT FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

- andrewinnocent.com
- **4**07-937-9003
- Cambridge, MA
- in andrewinnocent
- andrewinnocent

Skills

TECHNICAL

JavaScript

Ruby on Rails

Ember.js

HTML5

CSS3/Sass

jQuery

Bootstrap

Ruby

AJAX

Git/GitHub

Mongoose.js

Express.js

Node.js

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Handlebars

Heroku

ORGANIZATIONAL

Project Management

Public Speaking

Event Planning

Fundraising

Interests

MIT

Volunteer Seventh-day Adventist Chaplain

Kuumunity Collaborations

Workshop, perform, and record original music

World Travels

A dozen countries and counting!

Cooking

Pizza maker & enjoyer of all things vegetarian (except tempeh)

Summary

I'm a motivated, quick learning, and resourceful full-stack web developer with real-world experience working effectively in teams and engaging with clients. I'm excited to enter the web development industry and contribute technical and collaborative value to a mission-focused company.

Web Development Projects

Beaux-Ties

Utilizing the front-end framework Ember.js and building the API with Ruby on Rails, my capstone project is an e-commerce site selling bow-ties. Users can view, add to a wishlist, and add to/remove from a shopping cart. I wanted to make sure the experience was intuitive for users.

Bucket List

In this group project, a user can create and track their life goals in an easy-to-use way. New technologies used include Express, Node.js, Mongoose, and MongoDB for building the API. I gained experience working on an international team.

Here & There! A Travel Journal

A digital travel journal where users can CRUD journal entries about their travels across the USA. The API was built with Ruby on Rails. On the front-end, Handlebars.js and Bootstrap were used to clearly display journal entries.

Experience

Web Developer in Training

General Assembl

Boston, MA Jan 2018 to Apr 2018

- Successfully completed about 600 hours of in-class learning and self-study in a 12-week full-stack web development immersive program
- Growth-mindset instilled in order to quickly learn, understand, and implement new tools and concepts
- Created three individual and one group projects from ideation (wireframes, ERDs, user stories) to execution (deployed full-stack web apps); each was finished in one-week sprints
- Extensively used Git/GitHub for version control
- Introduced to and gained some experience with Agile/SCRUM development

 Director
 Cambridge, MA

 STRIDE, Inc.
 Aug 2012 to Current

- Collaborate with various stakeholders in organizing and implementing diverse weekly, monthly, and annual programs to support college students' spiritual, social, emotional, and physical well-being
- Manage organizational needs, like completing a two year process to gain 501(c)(3) non-profit status, applying for project funding (\$15,000+ over two years), and organizing fundraising campaigns (\$25,000+ in match campaigns over three years)
- Experience with public speaking and providing leadership training to students, churches, and national organizations
- Design and manage strideboston.org (using Squarespace), company Facebook page, and MailChimp newsletter

Customer Support Agent

INSTANT-2290.com

Cambridge, MA Apr 2016 to Jan 2018

- Assisted customers over the phone and/or via email to successfully electronically file the IRS Form 2290 in a timely fashion
- Drafted and finalized over two dozen FAQ and procedural articles for use by all CSAs a first for the company
- Effectively communicated customer pain points to supervisors and helped brainstorm solutions

Education

Bentley University

Masters Taxation 2009 Bachelors Accountancy 2008

Grenoble Graduate School of Business

Certificate Entrepreneurship Thinking 2009 Graduate Study Abroad Course in Grenoble, France